<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Automate everything</title><link>https://graef.io/</link><description>Automate everything - Sebastian Gräf</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 10:06:59 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://graef.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Conception, Construction and Evaluation of a Raspberry Pi Cluster</title><link>https://graef.io/conception-construction-and-evaluation-of-a-raspberry-pi-cluster/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://graef.io/conception-construction-and-evaluation-of-a-raspberry-pi-cluster/</guid><description>&lt;p>The goal of this work is to create an affordable, energy efficient and portable mini-supercomputer. Ideally, a cluster computer with little or no carbon footprint, individual elements that are inexpensive to replace, and a portable system that can be easily disassembled and reassembled.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How Github Copilot coding agent(s) make my day</title><link>https://graef.io/how-github-copilot-coding-agent-makes-my-day/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 10:06:59 +1000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://graef.io/how-github-copilot-coding-agent-makes-my-day/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ever wished you could delegate your coding tasks and watch them get done while you focus elsewhere? That’s exactly what happened when I assigned an issue to GitHub Copilot coding agent. From identifying the problem to drafting a pull request and running checks, it handled the entire workflow, efficiently and autonomously. Here&amp;rsquo;s how it turned a routine fix into a hands-free solution that saved me hours.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Automating Repository Management in Github and Azure Devops With Powershell</title><link>https://graef.io/automating-repository-management-in-github-and-azure-devops-with-powershell/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 10:22:10 +1000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://graef.io/automating-repository-management-in-github-and-azure-devops-with-powershell/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Working in large enterprise environments often means managing a complex landscape of repositories across multiple GitHub organizations and Azure DevOps projects. Keeping these repositories up to date—especially when working with multiple engineering teams—can be a daunting task. That’s where automation comes in.</p>
<p>To simplify this, I’ve developed a consolidated PowerShell script that combines the functionality of my previous scripts into one:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/segraef/Scripts/blob/main/PowerShell/Update-Repos.ps1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Update-Repos.ps1</a></li>
</ul>
<p>This script helps automate the process of cloning and updating repositories, making it significantly easier to manage a large number of repos efficiently.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Mastering DevOps: Your Guide to Learning, Certification, and Community Engagement</title><link>https://graef.io/devops-basics-studying-learning-and-skilling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 15:43:57 +1000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://graef.io/devops-basics-studying-learning-and-skilling/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>DevOps is not just a set of tools but a cultural shift towards automation, collaboration, and integration between software development and IT operations. Whether you&rsquo;re new to DevOps or looking to expand your expertise, it&rsquo;s essential to understand its key principles, tools, platforms, and methodologies. This post serves as a roadmap to help you navigate the journey of studying, learning, and becoming certified in DevOps.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Understanding the differences between OpenAI and Microsoft Azure OpenAI</title><link>https://graef.io/understanding-the-differences-between-openai-and-microsoft-azure-openai/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 08:13:11 +1000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://graef.io/understanding-the-differences-between-openai-and-microsoft-azure-openai/</guid><description>&lt;p>When comparing OpenAI and Microsoft Azure OpenAI, it’s important to recognize their unique strengths and collaborative potential. Both entities leverage cutting-edge AI technology, yet they serve different audiences and purposes, offering distinct features and benefits.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Create your own official Azure Pipelines Agent Images and GitHub Actions Runner Images</title><link>https://graef.io/create-your-own-official-azure-pipeline-agents-images-and-github-actions-runner-images/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 20:06:10 +1000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://graef.io/create-your-own-official-azure-pipeline-agents-images-and-github-actions-runner-images/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Let&rsquo;s create your own Azure Pipelines Agent Images or GitHub Actions Runner Images based on the official <a href="https://github.com/actions/runner-images/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">source code</a> used for <a href="https://docs.github.com/en/actions/using-github-hosted-runners/about-github-hosted-runners" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">GitHub-hosted runners</a> used for Actions, as well as for <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/devops/pipelines/agents/hosted?view=azure-devops#use-a-microsoft-hosted-agent" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Microsoft-hosted agents</a> used for Azure Pipelines. I prepared both Azure Pipelines and GitHub Workflow examples for you to choose from. It also can create your Virtual Machine Scale Set (VMSS) with the latest VM image to easily use for self-hosted scale-set agents in Azure DevOps.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Build your own GPT-Powered AI Voice Assistant with Azure OpenAI and Cognitive Services</title><link>https://graef.io/building-your-own-gpt-powered-ai-voice-assistant-with-azure-cognitive-services-and-openai/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 16:37:59 +1000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://graef.io/building-your-own-gpt-powered-ai-voice-assistant-with-azure-cognitive-services-and-openai/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Let&rsquo;s build your own AI voice assistant which is better than Amazon&rsquo;s <strong>Alexa</strong> using Azure Cognitive Services (SST and TTS) and OpenAI. All you need is a bit of basic Python understanding, an Azure account, a microphone and a speaker. This will take about 15 minutes to set up and you&rsquo;ll be done.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>From Code to Canvas: A Guide for Prompting Stunning AI Art with MidJourney (1/3)</title><link>https://graef.io/from-code-to-canvas-a-guide-for-prompting-stunning-ai-art-with-midjourney-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 14:12:25 +1000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://graef.io/from-code-to-canvas-a-guide-for-prompting-stunning-ai-art-with-midjourney-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>Unlock your artistic potential and create jaw-dropping AI art with these exclusive cheat codes for Midjourney. These expert hacks will take your art to new heights, no coding skills required!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>From Code to Canvas: A Guide for Prompting Stunning AI Art with MidJourney (2/3)</title><link>https://graef.io/from-code-to-canvas-a-guide-for-prompting-stunning-ai-art-with-midjourney-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 14:12:25 +1000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://graef.io/from-code-to-canvas-a-guide-for-prompting-stunning-ai-art-with-midjourney-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to the second part of guided prompting for Midjourney to unlock your artistic potential and create jaw-dropping AI art with exclusive cheat codes. These expert hacks will take your art to new heights, no coding skills required!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to REST the Have I Been Pwned (HIBP) API</title><link>https://graef.io/how-to-rest-have-i-been-pwned-hibp-api/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 16:12:12 +1000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://graef.io/how-to-rest-have-i-been-pwned-hibp-api/</guid><description>&lt;p>Perform REST API requests to the &lt;a href="https://haveibeenpwned.com/API/v3" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">HIBP API&lt;/a> to verify if your email or password have been involved in a data breach.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>