<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Other on Automate everything</title><link>https://graef.io/categories/other/</link><description>Recent content in Other on Automate everything</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 08:13:11 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://graef.io/categories/other/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Understanding the differences between OpenAI and Microsoft Azure OpenAI</title><link>https://graef.io/understanding-the-differences-between-openai-and-microsoft-azure-openai/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 08:13:11 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://graef.io/understanding-the-differences-between-openai-and-microsoft-azure-openai/</guid><description>&lt;p>When comparing OpenAI and Microsoft Azure OpenAI, it’s important to recognize their unique strengths and collaborative potential. Both entities leverage cutting-edge AI technology, yet they serve different audiences and purposes, offering distinct features and benefits.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Create your own official Azure Pipelines Agent Images and GitHub Actions Runner Images</title><link>https://graef.io/create-your-own-official-azure-pipeline-agents-images-and-github-actions-runner-images/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 20:06:10 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://graef.io/create-your-own-official-azure-pipeline-agents-images-and-github-actions-runner-images/</guid><description>&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s create your own Azure Pipelines Agent Images or GitHub Actions Runner Images based on the official &lt;a href="https://github.com/actions/runner-images/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">source code&lt;/a> used for &lt;a href="https://docs.github.com/en/actions/using-github-hosted-runners/about-github-hosted-runners" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">GitHub-hosted runners&lt;/a> used for Actions, as well as for &lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/devops/pipelines/agents/hosted?view=azure-devops#use-a-microsoft-hosted-agent" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Microsoft-hosted agents&lt;/a> used for Azure Pipelines. I prepared both Azure Pipelines and GitHub Workflow examples for you to choose from. It also can create your Virtual Machine Scale Set (VMSS) with the latest VM image to easily use for self-hosted scale-set agents in Azure DevOps.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to REST the Have I Been Pwned (HIBP) API</title><link>https://graef.io/how-to-rest-have-i-been-pwned-hibp-api/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 16:12:12 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://graef.io/how-to-rest-have-i-been-pwned-hibp-api/</guid><description>&lt;p>Perform REST API requests to the &lt;a href="https://haveibeenpwned.com/API/v3" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">HIBP API&lt;/a> to verify if your email or password have been involved in a data breach.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Understanding and Improving Your Cybersecurity Posture in 2023: The Importance of strong Passwords, 2FA and Awareness of Phishing Scams</title><link>https://graef.io/understanding-and-improving-your-cybersecurity-posture-the-importance-of-strong-passwords-2fa-and-awareness-of-phishing-scams/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 15:00:26 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://graef.io/understanding-and-improving-your-cybersecurity-posture-the-importance-of-strong-passwords-2fa-and-awareness-of-phishing-scams/</guid><description>&lt;p>Cybersecurity is the practice of protecting internet-connected systems, including hardware, software, and data, from attack, damage, or unauthorized access. One aspect of cybersecurity is protecting personal information, such as passwords, account data but also your privacy. In this article, we revisit the basics in cyber security, as there are daily new attacks and ways hackers try to get personal data.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Markdown Syntax Guide</title><link>https://graef.io/markdown-syntax-guide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://graef.io/markdown-syntax-guide/</guid><description>&lt;p>This article offers a sample of basic Markdown syntax that can be used in Hugo content files, also it shows whether basic HTML elements are decorated with CSS in a Hugo theme.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Set primary IP address order with multiple IP addresses on a NIC</title><link>https://graef.io/set-primary-ip-address-order-with-multiple-ip-addresses-on-a-nic/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 11:29:53 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://graef.io/set-primary-ip-address-order-with-multiple-ip-addresses-on-a-nic/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you’re running a webserver it may be you have to run different services on the same port and need to use multiple IP addresses on the same network interface. This can happen for SMTP or Exchange Servers using several connectors.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>