<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Automation - Tag - Automate everything</title><link>https://graef.io/tags/automation/</link><description>Automation - Tag - Automate everything</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 10:22:10 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://graef.io/tags/automation/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Automating Repository Management in Github and Azure Devops With Powershell</title><link>https://graef.io/automating-repository-management-in-github-and-azure-devops-with-powershell/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 10:22:10 +1000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://graef.io/automating-repository-management-in-github-and-azure-devops-with-powershell/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Working in large enterprise environments often means managing a complex landscape of repositories across multiple GitHub organizations and Azure DevOps projects. Keeping these repositories up to date—especially when working with multiple engineering teams—can be a daunting task. That’s where automation comes in.</p>
<p>To simplify this, I’ve developed a consolidated PowerShell script that combines the functionality of my previous scripts into one:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/segraef/Scripts/blob/main/PowerShell/Update-Repos.ps1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Update-Repos.ps1</a></li>
</ul>
<p>This script helps automate the process of cloning and updating repositories, making it significantly easier to manage a large number of repos efficiently.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Mastering DevOps: Your Guide to Learning, Certification, and Community Engagement</title><link>https://graef.io/devops-basics-studying-learning-and-skilling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 15:43:57 +1000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://graef.io/devops-basics-studying-learning-and-skilling/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>DevOps is not just a set of tools but a cultural shift towards automation, collaboration, and integration between software development and IT operations. Whether you&rsquo;re new to DevOps or looking to expand your expertise, it&rsquo;s essential to understand its key principles, tools, platforms, and methodologies. This post serves as a roadmap to help you navigate the journey of studying, learning, and becoming certified in DevOps.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>How to REST the Have I Been Pwned (HIBP) API</title><link>https://graef.io/how-to-rest-have-i-been-pwned-hibp-api/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 16:12:12 +1000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://graef.io/how-to-rest-have-i-been-pwned-hibp-api/</guid><description>&lt;p>Perform REST API requests to the &lt;a href="https://haveibeenpwned.com/API/v3" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">HIBP API&lt;/a> to verify if your email or password have been involved in a data breach.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Understanding and Improving Your Cybersecurity Posture in 2023: The Importance of strong Passwords, 2FA and Awareness of Phishing Scams</title><link>https://graef.io/understanding-and-improving-your-cybersecurity-posture-the-importance-of-strong-passwords-2fa-and-awareness-of-phishing-scams/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 15:00:26 +1000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://graef.io/understanding-and-improving-your-cybersecurity-posture-the-importance-of-strong-passwords-2fa-and-awareness-of-phishing-scams/</guid><description>&lt;p>Cybersecurity is the practice of protecting internet-connected systems, including hardware, software, and data, from attack, damage, or unauthorized access. One aspect of cybersecurity is protecting personal information, such as passwords, account data but also your privacy. In this article, we revisit the basics in cyber security, as there are daily new attacks and ways hackers try to get personal data.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fresh Development Setup within 10 Minutes using Winget</title><link>https://graef.io/fresh-development-machine-setup-using-winget-within-10-minutes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://graef.io/fresh-development-machine-setup-using-winget-within-10-minutes/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sometimes you have to setup your Laptop/Notebook fresh and also prepare your developer environment and tools you need. I noticed this again today when I rebooted my machine and spent almost 2 hours installing the tools I need to work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have put together a list of commands you can use to prepare your environment using Windows Package Manager (WinGet) for you which gives you a kick start at the next reset and you can continue working directly after 10 minutes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Find and replace with a newline in Visual Studio Code</title><link>https://graef.io/find-and-replace-with-a-newline-in-visual-studio-code/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 15:16:19 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://graef.io/find-and-replace-with-a-newline-in-visual-studio-code/</guid><description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p><strong>Today I learned</strong> How to <em><strong>find and replace</strong></em> with a newline in Visual Studio Code.</p></blockquote>
<p>In the local searchbox (<kbd>Ctrl</kbd> + <kbd>F</kbd>) you can insert newlines by pressing <kbd>Ctrl</kbd> + <kbd>Enter</kbd>.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Azure Pipelines Container Agents for Azure Devops</title><link>https://graef.io/azure-pipelines-container-agents-for-azure-devops/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 14:06:02 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://graef.io/azure-pipelines-container-agents-for-azure-devops/</guid><description>&lt;p>Create self-hosted Azure Pipelines Container Agents for Azure Devops.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Github Action for Project Bicep (ARM DSL)</title><link>https://graef.io/github-action-for-project-bicep-arm-dsl/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 17:52:23 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://graef.io/github-action-for-project-bicep-arm-dsl/</guid><description>&lt;p>All ARM enthusiasts among us will now probably cry out and be happy. Microsoft announced a new ARM DSL, called Bicep. I won’t go into too much detail here, as I’m more into how to use a GitHub Action to use Bicep to generate an ARM template out of a .bice file. But let me give you some context to &lt;a href="https://github.com/Azure/bicep" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Bicep&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Azure Github Actions and Workflows</title><link>https://graef.io/azure-github-actions-and-workflows/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 17:52:07 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://graef.io/azure-github-actions-and-workflows/</guid><description>&lt;p>Let me give you an introduction how to use the power of GitHub Actions and Workflows to deploy resources into Azure. I’m going to explain you the basics of GitHub Actions, Workflows, runners and how to deploy resources into Azure. At the end of this post you should have understood how GitHub Actions and Workflows work together to give you a kickstart to run your own.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Programmatically Create Azure Pipelines</title><link>https://graef.io/programmatically-create-azure-pipelines/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 13:10:29 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://graef.io/programmatically-create-azure-pipelines/</guid><description>&lt;p>This script &lt;a href="https://github.com/segraef/New-AzPipeline" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">New-AzPipeline&lt;/a> lets you programmatically create Azure Pipelines based on your folder structure.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>